<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>yandex_praktikum on Oleg Rofman</title>
    <link>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/tags/yandex_praktikum/</link>
    <description>Recent content in yandex_praktikum on Oleg Rofman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://olegrofman.github.io/en/tags/yandex_praktikum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of User Interaction with Yandex.Zen</title>
      <link>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/post/project-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/post/project-10/</guid>
      <description>Goals and objectives: construct a dashboard and analyze user interaction with the Yandex.Zen cards.
Input data: raw data from the database including events of user interaction with Yandex.Zen cards. Terms of reference for building a dashboard.
 Link to dashboard
Link to presentation
 I respect the rights of copyright holders of the course that belongs to Yandex.Prakticum and do not share a full description of the projects and their results in open access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Analysis of a Grocery Mobile Application</title>
      <link>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/post/project-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/post/project-9/</guid>
      <description>Goals and objectives: analyze the behavior of users who purchase food through a mobile application, and investigate the results of an A / A / B test showing the effect of changing the font in the application on user actions.
Input data: log records about user actions (events) of 3 experimental groups with time.
 Link to pdf (password required*)
Link to GitHub Repository (authorization and permission required*)
 I respect the rights of copyright holders of the course that belongs to Yandex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Models for Predicting Churn of Customers of a Network of Fitness Centers</title>
      <link>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/post/project-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/post/project-11/</guid>
      <description>Goals and objectives: analyze the data of the fitness center in order to develop a forecast of customer churn and recommend a strategy for their retention.
Input data: fitness center clients&#39; questionnaires, combined into a dataset according to a number of characteristics, including the client&amp;rsquo;s gender and age, the area of residence or work in relation to the location of fitness center, the client&amp;rsquo;s participation in the affiliate program, the use of a promo code, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catering Market in Moscow</title>
      <link>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/post/project-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/post/project-8/</guid>
      <description>Goals and objectives: analyze the current status in the Moscow catering market in order to develop recommendations for investors on opening a cafe with robotic waiters.
Input data: data on public catering companies in Moscow showing the name and type of public catering service, its affiliation to the network distribution, location and number of seats.
External data: external data were used to obtain additional information about the administrative and territorial division of Moscow, as well as geodata of real estate objects in which catering companies and corresponding districts are located.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis Prioritization and Analysis of A/B Test Data</title>
      <link>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/post/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/post/project-7/</guid>
      <description>Goals and objectives: identify priority hypotheses aimed at increasing revenue, as well as analyze the results of an A/B test conducted using data from an online store.
Input data: (1) a list of hypotheses proposed in order to increase the revenue of the online store, and their quantitative assessment according to various criteria (coverage and impact on users, confidence in the hypothesis, cost estimation); (2) A / B test data with information about visitors to the online store and their orders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Marketing Analytics for Yandex.Afisha</title>
      <link>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>Goals and objectives: analyze data on visits and orders of customers from the Yandex.Afisha website, as well as related advertising costs to highlight unprofitable traffic sources and make recommendations to the marketing department on budget redistribution.
Input data: server logs with information about visits and orders from the Yandex.Afisha website, as well as information about marketing costs for the period from June 2017 to the end of May 2018.
Link to pdf (password required*)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airline Data Analytics</title>
      <link>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Goals and objectives: to process a small sample data set with information about the airline&amp;rsquo;s activities in a given period of time in order to analyze the average number of flights to each city and the aircraft models involved.
Input data: two results of queries from the airline&amp;rsquo;s database with information (i) about the aircraft model and the number of flights for each model in September 2018 and (ii) about the cities and the average number of flights arriving there per day in August 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Tariff for a Telecom Company</title>
      <link>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Goals and objectives: to analyze on a small sample data set, the behavior of customers of the Megaline mobile operator using the Smart and Ultra tariffs. Help to determine which tariff provides the maximum revenue and what factors affect it.
Input data: a sample data set on 500 Megaline clients with information about their name, age, place of residence, tariff connected, etc., calls / messages / Internet session (date, call duration, traffic volume) and tariff data (subscription fee, service packages, conditions in excess of the tariff package).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaming &amp; Video Game Data Analytics</title>
      <link>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://olegrofman.github.io/en/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Goals and objectives: analyze data from a global online store and identify patterns that determine the success of a computer game as a potentially popular product.
Input data: a selection of data from a global online store (more than 16k unique values) with information about the gaming platform, game name, its year of release and genre; game sales by region; critics / users ratings and age ratings.
 Link to pdf (password required*)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
